<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sequoias on the papers</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sequoias/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sequoias on the papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 19:47:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sequoias/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/think-about-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/think-about-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;=&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-of-sequoia-trails&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;things of sequoia trails&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;yall-said-it&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&amp;rsquo;all said it!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;THERE ARE ORANGE TREES EVERYWHERE IN THE SAN JUAQUIN VALLEY&#xA;&#39;EVERYBODY THERE IS SO NICE&#39;&#xA;&#39;I REALLY ADMIRE THAT YOU LIKE PHYSICS&#39;&#xA;&#39;WE HAVE STICK AT HOME!&#39;&#xA;&#39;THE MOUNTAIN IS CALLING ME&#39;&#xA;&#39;IT&#39;S JUST THE PARASITIC TICKS&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;its-hard-to-describe-the-feelings-i-have-a-lot-of-gratitude-for-the-experiences-im-earning-eddie-talked-about-viberations-but-that-feels-too-loud-butchs-intertwanglism-is-too-culturally-specific-both-were-onto-something-though-when-you-begin-to-see-it-you-cant-unsee-it-the-egg-the-universe-yada-yada-yes--but-magic-spirits-living-earth-theres-something-out-there-and-yesterday-i-felt-it-felt-today-i-saw-it-but-looks-and-feels-are-quite-different-in-this-place-a-visual-version-of-the-realm-of-sonorous-being&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to describe the feelings I have. A lot of gratitude for the experiences I&amp;rsquo;m earning. Eddie talked about &lt;i&gt;viberations&lt;/i&gt;, but that feels &lt;em&gt;too loud&lt;/em&gt;. Butch&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;intertwanglism&lt;/i&gt; is too culturally specific. Both were onto something though. When you begin to see it, you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it. &lt;i&gt;The Egg&lt;/i&gt;, the &lt;b&gt;Universe&lt;/b&gt;, yada yada, yes- &lt;b&gt;BUT&lt;/b&gt;. Magic, spirits, living earth. There&amp;rsquo;s something &lt;em&gt;OUT THERE&lt;/EM&gt;. And yesterday I &lt;u&gt;felt&lt;/u&gt; it. Felt? Today I &lt;u&gt;SAW&lt;/u&gt; it. But looks and feels are quite different in this place. A visual version of the &lt;i&gt;Realm of Sonorous Being&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;what-is-all-of-this&#34;&gt;What is all of this?&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The snow made me very happy. I was elated we got to experience the park in this &amp;lsquo;&lt;i&gt;off season&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo; way.&#xA;Being is fun. Existing is rewarding.&#xA;All these questions make me happy.&#xA;The gratitude grows. I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself being grateful for the pain, fear, and anxiety as much as the awe, the love, and the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/the-national-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/the-national-parks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-national-parks&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;the national parks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;where-to-even-begin-the-last-few-days-have-been-so-packed-with-experiences-i-cant-keep-my-head-on-straight-i-reckon-ill-do-things-the-julie-andrews-way-and-start-from-the-very-beginning&#34;&gt;Where to even begin? The last few days have been so packed with experiences I can&amp;rsquo;t keep my head on straight. I reckon I&amp;rsquo;ll do things the Julie Andrews way and start from the very beginning.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;after-we-arrived-in-fresno-we-met-with-our-friends-and-got-our-car-for-dinner-we-had-in-n-out-which-for-most-of-us-was-our-first-time-the-way-they-chop-those-gigantic-potatoes-is-comical-and-hilarious-after-dinner-we-made-our-way-to-the-grocery-then-the-airbnb-and-crashed&#34;&gt;After we arrived in Fresno, we met with our friends and got our car. For dinner we had In-N-Out, which for most of us was our first time. The way they chop those gigantic potatoes is comical and hilarious. After dinner we made our way to the grocery then the AirBnb and crashed.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-next-morning-we-all-got-up-extra-early-for-our-long-drive-to-yosemite-national-park-we-got-to-see-most-of-the-big-hitters-el-capitan-the-half-dome-a-grove-of-giant-sequoias-meadows-and-waterfalls-we-got-so-wet-at-the-falls-everyone-was-grinning-like-a-dead-pig-and-had-the-giggles-at-the-yosemite-post-office-why-yes-there-is-a-post-office-in-the-park-i-got-my-notebook-stamped-with-the-special-note-they-have-for-mail-coming-out-of-the-park-the-drive-back-was-more-outrageous-than-the-drive-in-because-at-least-when-youre-driving-in-you-get-to-see-some-sights-at-night-its-pitch-black-in-them-hills&#34;&gt;The next morning we all got up extra early for our long drive to Yosemite National Park. We got to see most of the big hitters, El Capitan, the Half Dome, a grove of giant sequoias, meadows and waterfalls. We got so wet at the falls, everyone was grinning like a dead pig and had the giggles. At the Yosemite Post Office, why yes, there is a post office in the park, I got my notebook stamped with the special note they have for mail coming out of the park. The drive back was more outrageous than the drive in, because at least when you&amp;rsquo;re driving in, you get to see some sights. At night it&amp;rsquo;s pitch black in them hills.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;yesterday-we-made-our-way-to-sequoia-national-park-that-much-i-know-today-and-yesterday-are-kinda-running-together-for-me-because-were-getting-started-at-the-crack-of-dawn-and-crashing-at-11pm-we-went-through-the-foothills-of-the-park-and-saw-tunnel-rock-and-hospital-rock-then-made-our-way-up-to-higher-altitude-where-we-climbed-to-the-top-of-the-mountain-and-saw-some-really-neat-sequoias-we-hiked-back-down-so-we-could-then-visit-the-worlds-largest-tree-general-sherman-a-monument-to-say-the-least-however-we-were-all-quite-tired-at-that-point-and-had-some-more-places-in-mind-we-ended-the-day-by-watching-the-sunset-from-the-side-of-the-mountain-where-we-met-some-deer&#34;&gt;Yesterday we made our way to Sequoia National Park, that much I know. Today and yesterday are kinda running together for me because were getting started at the crack of dawn and crashing at 11PM. We went through the foothills of the park and saw Tunnel Rock and Hospital Rock then made our way up to higher altitude where we climbed to the top of the mountain and saw some really neat sequoias. We hiked back down so we could then visit the worlds largest tree, General Sherman. A monument to say the least, however we were all quite tired at that point and had some more places in mind. We ended the day by watching the sunset from the side of the mountain where we met some deer.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;today-we-fortunately-didnt-have-to-wait-on-a-road-closure-to-clear-up-for-us-to-get-into-the-main-area-of-sequoia-national-park-but-we-did-have-eminent-road-closures-due-to-a-winter-advisory-and-possible-snow-we-took-the-main-road-that-traverses-through-sequoia-and-into-formerly-known-as-grant-park-this-area-now-part-of-kings-canyon-has-another-one-of-the-largest-trees-in-the-world-the-second-to-be-more-specific-the-general-grant-tree-is-a-lot-more-impressive-in-my-opinion-than-the-sherman-tree-a-guide-explained-that-grant-grows-at-a-much-more-rapid-pace-than-sherman-so-if-all-goes-well-itll-be-the-largest-in-some-hundred-years-we-made-a-stop-on-the-way-out-of-kings-canyon-but-hustled-out-to-be-sure-the-road-didnt-close-on-us-lest-we-wanted-to-drive-out-around-our-elbow-to-get-to-our-ass-our-last-stop-was-tokopah-falls-the-hike-followed-marble-fork-of-kaweah-river-and-it-is-just-stunning-the-trail-is-likely-one-of-my-personal-favorites-as-we-approached-the-falls-it-slowly-began-to-snow-on-us-the-closer-we-got-the-more-it-snowed-we-made-it-right-up-to-a-great-view-of-the-falls-when-we-decided-to-turn-around-it-kept-snowing-it-kept-snowing-more-joshua-and-our-friends-were-getting-a-little-nervous-i-was-still-awestruck-beyond-worries-the-snow-was-beautiful-the-trees-were-beautiful-the-rapids-the-flurries-the-wet-soggy-soil-the-fog-the-clouds-the-wall-of-rock-scaling-your-whole-view-all-so-beautiful-we-made-it-back-safe-and-sound-no-tire-chains-needed-and-no-snow-on-the-roads&#34;&gt;Today we fortunately didn&amp;rsquo;t have to wait on a road closure to clear up for us to get into the main area of Sequoia National Park. But&amp;hellip; we did have eminent road closures due to a winter advisory and possible snow. We took the main road that traverses through Sequoia and into formerly known as Grant Park. This area, now part of Kings Canyon, has another one of the largest trees in the world, the second, to be more specific. The General Grant tree is a lot more impressive in my opinion than the Sherman tree. A guide explained that Grant grows at a much more rapid pace than Sherman, so if all goes well, it&amp;rsquo;ll be the largest in some hundred years. We made a stop on the way out of Kings Canyon, but hustled out to be sure the road didn&amp;rsquo;t close on us, lest we wanted to drive out around our elbow to get to our ass. Our last stop was Tokopah Falls. The hike followed Marble Fork of Kaweah River, and it is just stunning. The trail is likely one of my personal favorites. As we approached the falls, it slowly began to snow on us. The closer we got, the more it snowed. We made it right up to a great view of the falls, when we decided to turn around. It kept snowing. It kept snowing more. Joshua and our friends were getting a little nervous, I was still awestruck beyond worries. The snow was beautiful, the trees were beautiful, the rapids, the flurries, the wet soggy soil, the fog, the clouds, the wall of rock scaling your whole view. All so beautiful. We made it back safe and sound, no tire chains needed, and no snow on the roads.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-land-here-has-an-energy-that-is-hard-to-describe-with-words-its-serene-and-spiritual-monumental-and-cleansing-pure-and-sacred-theres-a-feeling-about-the-air-that-feels-like-a-spirit-of-some-kind-maybe-the-mountain-maybe-the-river-or-the-trees-its-hard-to-wrap-your-head-around-a-place-that-took-millions-of-years-to-develop-and-organisms-that-took-hundreds-or-even-thousands-of-years-to-grow-to-where-they-are-now-when-i-blink-i-see-flashes-of-the-seminal-landscape-that-we-were-so-fortunate-to-see-this-week-i-feel-overwhelmed-with-gratitude-in-this-moment-but-also-inspired-to-make-and-inspired-to-do-im-eager-to-see-what-come-of-this-experience&#34;&gt;The land here has an energy that is hard to describe with words. It&amp;rsquo;s serene and spiritual, monumental and cleansing, pure and sacred. There&amp;rsquo;s a feeling about the air that feels like a spirit of some kind, maybe the mountain, maybe the river, or the trees. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to wrap your head around a place that took millions of years to develop, and organisms that took hundreds, or even thousands of years to grow to where they are now. When I blink, I see flashes of the seminal landscape that we were so fortunate to see this week. I feel overwhelmed with gratitude in this moment but also inspired to make and inspired to do. I&amp;rsquo;m eager to see what come of this experience.&lt;/h6&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/california-girlie-pops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/california-girlie-pops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;california-girlie-pops&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;california girlie-pops&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;today-the-girlies-and-i-are-on-the-way-out-to-california-five-of-us-are-meeting-in-fresno-to-drive-out-to-an-accommodation-just-between-yosemite-kings-canyon-and-the-giant-sequoias-were-all-super-excited-to-experience-these-monuments-together-its-particularly-special-because-these-are-some-of-our-closest-friends-and-itll-be-one-of-the-last-big-things-we-get-to-do-together-while-we-all-live-in-georgia&#34;&gt;Today the girlies and I are on the way out to California. Five of us are meeting in Fresno to drive out to an accommodation just between Yosemite, Kings Canyon, and the Giant Sequoias. We&amp;rsquo;re all super excited to experience these monuments together. It&amp;rsquo;s particularly special because these are some of our closest friends, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be one of the last big things we get to do together while we all live in Georgia.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;joshua-planned-the-whole-thing-the-way-he-does-im-so-grateful-hes-headstrong-about-planning-because-i-am-not-i-want-it-all-to-just-happen-and-enjoy-the-ride-hes-so-excited-for-this-trip-hes-bought-binoculars-a-harness-a-new-flashlight-new-boots-jackets-the-whole-get-up-of-course-everything-that-can-be-is-in-the-color-green&#34;&gt;Joshua planned the whole thing, the way he does. I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful he&amp;rsquo;s headstrong about planning, because I am not. I want it all to just happen and enjoy the ride. He&amp;rsquo;s so excited for this trip; he&amp;rsquo;s bought binoculars, a harness, a new flashlight, new boots, jackets, the whole get-up. Of course, everything that can be is in the color green.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;ive-packed-a-notebook-i-made-especially-for-the-month-of-may-in-addition-to-my-regular-sketchbook-i-aim-to-take-both-out-to-the-parks-each-day-and-have-study-time-i-think-i-speak-for-most-of-us-when-i-say-we-need-time-to-sit-and-draw-and-write-a-professor-of-ours-always-says-writing-is-thinking-like-most-i-didnt-quite-get-the-advice-until-i-had-sat-with-it-and-experienced-it-for-myself-writing-is-thinking-but-drawing-is-too-as-visual-artists-we-all-need-the-time-to-sketch-ideas-jot-notes-and-study-the-world-by-translating-it-to-paper&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve packed a notebook I made especially for the month of May in addition to my regular sketchbook. I aim to take both out to the parks each day and have study time. I think I speak for most of us when I say we &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt; time to sit and draw and write. A professor of ours always says, &amp;ldquo;Writing is thinking.&amp;rdquo; Like most, I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get the advice until I had sat with it and experienced it for myself. Writing &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thinking, but drawing is too. As visual artists, we all need the time to sketch ideas, jot notes, and study the world by translating it to paper.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;ill-end-with-a-poem-i-wrote-for-someone-on-the-trip-their-birthday-was-yesterday&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll end with a poem I wrote for someone on the trip. Their birthday was yesterday.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA;ardent instinct, namely sharp language, ensonorous yen.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;free as yon river, ever-nesting endeavors.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;so tend each edition, value eclipsed suns.&#xA;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
