<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Annie-Schwartz on the papers</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/annie-schwartz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Annie-Schwartz on the papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/annie-schwartz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/im-actually-a-birder-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/im-actually-a-birder-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;=&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;19-may-2025&#34;&gt;19 MAY 2025&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;fuck- i remember, i remember that first day Will took me out. I remember thinking I kinda knew some birds but had no idea the vastness of the world of birding. I remember telling him a bird made a certain call that was absolutely wrong and he just nodded and let it go. He was so patient and I could tell, even then, that he knew I had no idea what I was getting myself into. He could sense that there was something in me that would latch on and figure it out. Here I am at the first sip of my inaugural New England Summer. Will is moving on and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a hard time with that. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been dealing with a lot of rough emotions around him, but I&amp;rsquo;m starting to have peace with it. I wish so much that I could spend more time with him. I wish I could see him as often as I do for the foreseeable future, but I can&amp;rsquo;t. We&amp;rsquo;re at two different places in life.&#xA;But I&amp;rsquo;m a birder now. I&amp;rsquo;m a birder thanks to him, but also thanks to my crazy autistic brain. I get so excited by these creatures marching and fluttering around outside. They&amp;rsquo;re dumb, they&amp;rsquo;re sweet, they&amp;rsquo;re sometimes pretty annoying, but they&amp;rsquo;re beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s lovely to have so many reasons to go outside. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I rushed Annie out of my house because I wanted to go to Mansfield Hollow before twilight was over. I should mention that, of course, she was invited, but she had things to take care of.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to not just recognize birds by sight, song, call, and name, but people in the birding community too. I&amp;rsquo;m learning names of people who frequent the eBird reports in Connecticut. I&amp;rsquo;ve met three other prominent birders around my age and one lovely gentleman who showed Will and I where the West Virginia Whites were. I&amp;rsquo;ve even made pals with &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; David Mathieu. Which I have to admit, I had no idea how much of a celebrity he was until after I began birding with him. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to tell him sometime about my naive self emailing him and Aiden Kiley on the fly asking to bird together. I&amp;rsquo;m so thankful David replied, I feel we click and I feel we could get to become good pals. I&amp;rsquo;d like to invite him to a yard party when we have one this summer. Invite him to see some art or other non-birding things. I wonder what his life is like outside of birding. I wondered that about Will for a while, but I slowly learned that, other than school, he spends much of his private time surfing the naturalist web.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ll be eternally grateful for Will for giving me almost an entire year of teaching. Without him, I would have never gotten to the point I am at such a swift pace. It was around this time last year I was wishing I could identify birds the way I can now. I remember &lt;a href=&#34;07.the-papers/content/01/the%20chattahoochee%20valley%20beats%20like%20a%20heart.md&#34;&gt;the chattahoochee valley beats like a heart&lt;/a&gt; and hearing all the birds. I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; the whippoorwill, after all.. I remember being in California wishing I were a birder because I&amp;rsquo;d be in heaven. It was just a year ago and I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been just a year. I&amp;rsquo;m actually a birder now, and I can honestly say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been so happy in such a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
