<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>journal on the papers</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in journal on the papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>a letter to kate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/a-letter-to-kate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/a-letter-to-kate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;its-rare-to-meet-someone-who-stands-out-as-a-true-example-of-what-being-a-good-human-means-since-meeting-you-last-year-you-quickly-became-someone-i-look-up-to-there-are-an-abundance-of-reasons-i-am-grateful-for-you&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s rare to meet someone who stands out as a true example of what being a &amp;lsquo;good human&amp;rsquo; means. Since meeting you last year, you quickly became someone I look up to. There are an abundance of reasons I am grateful for you.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;youre-so-incredibly-kind-and-patient-and-caring-youre-especially-hardworking-and-youre-joyful-and-hilarious-even-when-you-handle-conflict-with-such-grace-you-let-people-know-when-they-need-to-get-their-act-together&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re so incredibly kind and patient and caring. You&amp;rsquo;re especially hardworking. &lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re joyful, and hilarious. Even when you handle conflict with such grace, you let people know when they need to get their act together.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-appreciate-your-support-in-each-part-of-my-life-from-my-studio-practice-to-birding-and-ensuring-im-able-to-make-ends-meet&#34;&gt;I appreciate your support in each part of my life, from my studio practice, to birding, and ensuring I&amp;rsquo;m able to make ends meet.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;no-amount-of-writing-or-words-can-express-the-amount-of-gratitude-i-have-to-know-you-to-be-so-trusted-by-you-you-are-such-a-wonderful-mentor-role-model-and-friend&#34;&gt;No amount of writing or words can express the amount of gratitude I have to know you, to be so trusted by you. You are such a wonderful mentor, role model, and friend.&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/the-tangerine-boy-is-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 08:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/the-tangerine-boy-is-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s back and I&amp;rsquo;m already having feelings of missing out. He&amp;rsquo;s looking at a Fork-tailed Flycatcher down in New Haven. I kinda wish I had gone. The bird is cool, it would&amp;rsquo;ve been even cooler to see him. He also tried for the Anhinga yesterday, it&amp;rsquo;s also back. I want to be around his excitement for the birds again. I want his endless information dump. I want his contagious curiosity.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll see him again someday, I&amp;rsquo;m just not sure when. It&amp;rsquo;s clear Joshua hates him and the thought of him now.&#xA;I feel like a part of me is missing or empty knowing he&amp;rsquo;s so close and moving through life. I wonder what he&amp;rsquo;s feeling. I wonder what drives him to seek out the birds.&#xA;It seems love drives my curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/im-actually-a-birder-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/im-actually-a-birder-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;=&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;19-may-2025&#34;&gt;19 MAY 2025&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;fuck- i remember, i remember that first day Will took me out. I remember thinking I kinda knew some birds but had no idea the vastness of the world of birding. I remember telling him a bird made a certain call that was absolutely wrong and he just nodded and let it go. He was so patient and I could tell, even then, that he knew I had no idea what I was getting myself into. He could sense that there was something in me that would latch on and figure it out. Here I am at the first sip of my inaugural New England Summer. Will is moving on and I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a hard time with that. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been dealing with a lot of rough emotions around him, but I&amp;rsquo;m starting to have peace with it. I wish so much that I could spend more time with him. I wish I could see him as often as I do for the foreseeable future, but I can&amp;rsquo;t. We&amp;rsquo;re at two different places in life.&#xA;But I&amp;rsquo;m a birder now. I&amp;rsquo;m a birder thanks to him, but also thanks to my crazy autistic brain. I get so excited by these creatures marching and fluttering around outside. They&amp;rsquo;re dumb, they&amp;rsquo;re sweet, they&amp;rsquo;re sometimes pretty annoying, but they&amp;rsquo;re beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s lovely to have so many reasons to go outside. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I rushed Annie out of my house because I wanted to go to Mansfield Hollow before twilight was over. I should mention that, of course, she was invited, but she had things to take care of.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to not just recognize birds by sight, song, call, and name, but people in the birding community too. I&amp;rsquo;m learning names of people who frequent the eBird reports in Connecticut. I&amp;rsquo;ve met three other prominent birders around my age and one lovely gentleman who showed Will and I where the West Virginia Whites were. I&amp;rsquo;ve even made pals with &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; David Mathieu. Which I have to admit, I had no idea how much of a celebrity he was until after I began birding with him. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to tell him sometime about my naive self emailing him and Aiden Kiley on the fly asking to bird together. I&amp;rsquo;m so thankful David replied, I feel we click and I feel we could get to become good pals. I&amp;rsquo;d like to invite him to a yard party when we have one this summer. Invite him to see some art or other non-birding things. I wonder what his life is like outside of birding. I wondered that about Will for a while, but I slowly learned that, other than school, he spends much of his private time surfing the naturalist web.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ll be eternally grateful for Will for giving me almost an entire year of teaching. Without him, I would have never gotten to the point I am at such a swift pace. It was around this time last year I was wishing I could identify birds the way I can now. I remember &lt;a href=&#34;07.the-papers/content/01/the%20chattahoochee%20valley%20beats%20like%20a%20heart.md&#34;&gt;the chattahoochee valley beats like a heart&lt;/a&gt; and hearing all the birds. I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; the whippoorwill, after all.. I remember being in California wishing I were a birder because I&amp;rsquo;d be in heaven. It was just a year ago and I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s been just a year. I&amp;rsquo;m actually a birder now, and I can honestly say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been so happy in such a long time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/birds-on-the-roof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/birds-on-the-roof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The little house sparrows keep oscillating from the bush out front to the ledge of the roof. Occasionally their wings all flutter at the same moment resulting in a sound that almost resembles sudden rainfall.&#xA;The coffee was pretty good this morning, I quite like the one I got from the local co-op.&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;&amp;hellip;&#xA;It sure is busy this morning.&#xA;I spoke with Ainsley on Facetime for what started out as a conversation about hollandaise sauce. I haven&amp;rsquo;t got a clue how to make it, but I&amp;rsquo;ve substituted with a mixture of mayonnaise, mustard, and vinegar a few times. We chatted about plants, settling into our new spaces and places. I was reminded about the similarities here with home, but also the differences.&#xA;Its neat how close these birds are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>northeast corridor life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/northeast-corridor-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/northeast-corridor-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been in Connecticut for just over a week now. Settling in has definitely had its stressful moments, but  overall the move has been smooth. Our friends Ainsley and Gena arrived last Saturday to help us get the bulk of unpacking done. All four of us have moved within the last three months.&#xA;On Thursday we visited Wesleyan&amp;rsquo;s campus, where I&amp;rsquo;ll be working for the next eight or so months. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s a path for me to keep working there more long term, given I don&amp;rsquo;t get worn out by the hour-long commute in my &amp;lsquo;02 Tacoma each day. The campus is absolutely beautiful and the arts buildings spit brutalism in your face. A nice feature of the buildings is most a connected via an underground tunnel. Moreover, my supervisor, Kate, is super pleasant and excited to work with me just as much as I am her.&#xA;Before we know it, Joshua will be starting his classes. I know he&amp;rsquo;s excited, but he is even more excited to have a studio with lots and lots of studio time. His work lately has been insanely curious and wills me to study things I hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered before. This new wave of interest he&amp;rsquo;s had is full of gumption and typical Joshua spirit, and it makes me oh so eager to see his upcoming journey.&#xA;Leaving Georgia was quite a tough decision, but every step of the way, not a single doubt took root. We both feel in our hearts that this was the best decision for us and we are both just content to be together in this new place. I told Joshua on Thursday, on the way back from Middletown, I was so scared I would feel a hole leaving our friends back in Georgia, but in fact I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the love we all have for each other is so strong, that couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth. The hole I was worried about is overflowing with love, and I&amp;rsquo;m ready to fill it with more with new friends here in Connecticut.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/gotcha-covered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 11:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/gotcha-covered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;its-funny-that-my-bucket-list-from-2015-still-on-my-reminders-app-has-these-things&#34;&gt;Its funny that my bucket list from 2015, still on my Reminders app, has these things&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Lana Del Rey Concert&#xA;Skiing&#xA;Wicked&#xA;Providence Canyon Stars&#xA;North Georgia Waterfalls&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Joshua has made damn sure I don&amp;rsquo;t even need a bucket list. He&amp;rsquo;s got me covered. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen Wicked on Broadway at this point, and the others we&amp;rsquo;re just not as interested in. We&amp;rsquo;ve got plenty of other experiences under our belt at this point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/thoughts-on-markdown-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 09:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/thoughts-on-markdown-et-al/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;im-starting-to-get-the-hang-of-this-markdown-thing&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get the hang of this markdown thing.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting what you can do with tags, properties, and simpler formatting. I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite standardized yet how I want my notes to look and whatnot, but It&amp;rsquo;ll happen naturally as I go. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m really gung-ho on getting my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/recipes/&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; organized and standardized. After that, I&amp;rsquo;d love to start experimenting with custom #CSS classes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;also-on-my-mind-is-this-hair-experiment-im-doing-to-myself&#34;&gt;Also on my mind is this hair experiment I&amp;rsquo;m doing to myself.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m deciding to forgo shampoo in favor of hair washes I can make at home. It seems there are a lot of recipes online, mostly popular in India. The one I made first has a lot of turmeric in it, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about its natural ability to dye things a bright yellow. Thankfully it washes right out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/think-about-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/think-about-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;=&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-of-sequoia-trails&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;things of sequoia trails&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;yall-said-it&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&amp;rsquo;all said it!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;THERE ARE ORANGE TREES EVERYWHERE IN THE SAN JUAQUIN VALLEY&#xA;&#39;EVERYBODY THERE IS SO NICE&#39;&#xA;&#39;I REALLY ADMIRE THAT YOU LIKE PHYSICS&#39;&#xA;&#39;WE HAVE STICK AT HOME!&#39;&#xA;&#39;THE MOUNTAIN IS CALLING ME&#39;&#xA;&#39;IT&#39;S JUST THE PARASITIC TICKS&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;its-hard-to-describe-the-feelings-i-have-a-lot-of-gratitude-for-the-experiences-im-earning-eddie-talked-about-viberations-but-that-feels-too-loud-butchs-intertwanglism-is-too-culturally-specific-both-were-onto-something-though-when-you-begin-to-see-it-you-cant-unsee-it-the-egg-the-universe-yada-yada-yes--but-magic-spirits-living-earth-theres-something-out-there-and-yesterday-i-felt-it-felt-today-i-saw-it-but-looks-and-feels-are-quite-different-in-this-place-a-visual-version-of-the-realm-of-sonorous-being&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to describe the feelings I have. A lot of gratitude for the experiences I&amp;rsquo;m earning. Eddie talked about &lt;i&gt;viberations&lt;/i&gt;, but that feels &lt;em&gt;too loud&lt;/em&gt;. Butch&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;intertwanglism&lt;/i&gt; is too culturally specific. Both were onto something though. When you begin to see it, you can&amp;rsquo;t unsee it. &lt;i&gt;The Egg&lt;/i&gt;, the &lt;b&gt;Universe&lt;/b&gt;, yada yada, yes- &lt;b&gt;BUT&lt;/b&gt;. Magic, spirits, living earth. There&amp;rsquo;s something &lt;em&gt;OUT THERE&lt;/EM&gt;. And yesterday I &lt;u&gt;felt&lt;/u&gt; it. Felt? Today I &lt;u&gt;SAW&lt;/u&gt; it. But looks and feels are quite different in this place. A visual version of the &lt;i&gt;Realm of Sonorous Being&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;what-is-all-of-this&#34;&gt;What is all of this?&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The snow made me very happy. I was elated we got to experience the park in this &amp;lsquo;&lt;i&gt;off season&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo; way.&#xA;Being is fun. Existing is rewarding.&#xA;All these questions make me happy.&#xA;The gratitude grows. I&amp;rsquo;m finding myself being grateful for the pain, fear, and anxiety as much as the awe, the love, and the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/heading-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/heading-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading-home&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;heading home&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;6 May 2024 9:46AM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;tags&#34;&gt;tags:&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;#feelings #gratitude #gardens #museum #art&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;sitting-at-the-airport-right-now-waiting-for-our-first-of-two-flights-to-get-home-yesterday-we-had-a-pretty-easy-day-with-the-winter-advisory-stil-in-effect-for-most-of-the-parks-we-didnt-feels-safe-going-back-for-the-last-day-you-could-see-the-storms-in-the-mountains-from-our-accomodation-that-morning-we-made-a-big-breakfast-to-try-and-use-up-as-many-groceries-as-we-could&#34;&gt;Sitting at the airport right now waiting for our first of two flights to get home. Yesterday we had a pretty easy day. With the winter advisory stil in effect for most of the parks, we didn&amp;rsquo;t feels safe going back for the last day. You could see the storms in the mountains from our accomodation. That morning, we made a big breakfast to try and use up as many groceries as we could.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;with-that-we-took-a-day-trip-to-fresno-we-explored-a-japanese-garden-that-was-located-in-a-park-this-garden-was-serene-and-full-of-flora-from-its-namesake-we-saw-an-exhibition-of-bonsai-some-over-1000-years-old-some-koi-and-a-few-peacocks-and-peahens&#34;&gt;With that, we took a day trip to Fresno. We explored a Japanese Garden that was located in a park. This garden was serene and full of flora from it&amp;rsquo;s namesake. We saw an exhibition of bonsai, some over 1000 years old, some koi, and a few peacocks and peahens.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;following-the-japanese-garden-we-grabbed-lunch-and-made-our-way-to-the-fresno-art-museum-they-had-a-wonderful-exhibit-of-uykio-e-prints-from-the-collection-of-the-georgia-museum-of-art-go-figure-they-also-had-an-exhibiton-on-trading-cards-a-secret-war-photographer-and-judy-wayne-seems-they-have-a-thing-for-2d-work-more-specifically-printed-work-the-wayne-exhibition-was-especailly-interesting-with-the-use-of-negative-imagry-lithography-and-the-type-and-color-of-paper-she-chose-the-work-was-an-exploration-of-her-mother-a-single-working-mom-during-the-40s-and-50s-when-that-was-unheard-of-there-i-also-spoke-with-two-locals-for-quite-some-time-who-were-very-curious-about-what-brought-me-to-fresno-and-what-its-like-in-georgia-it-was-interesting-to-me-that-they-think-of-georgia-as-having-a-much-higher-crime-rate-than-here-in-california&#34;&gt;Following the Japanese Garden we grabbed lunch and made our way to the Fresno Art Museum. They had a wonderful exhibit of uykio-e prints from the collection of the Georgia Museum of Art, go figure! They also had an exhibiton on trading cards, a secret war photographer, and Judy Wayne. Seem&amp;rsquo;s they have a thing for 2D work, more specifically printed work. The Wayne exhibition was especailly interesting with the use of negative imagry, lithography, and the type and color of paper she chose. The work was an exploration of her mother, a single working mom during the 40s and 50s, when that was unheard of. There I also spoke with two locals for quite some time who were very curious about what brought me to Fresno and what it&amp;rsquo;s like in Georgia. It was interesting to me that they think of Georgia as having a much higher crime rate than here in California.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;following-the-museum-we-visited-another-garden-covis-botanical-which-is-all-volunteer-run-this-garden-was-very-nice-especially-to-be-completely-run-by-volunteers-i-sat-for-a-while-under-a-tree-and-jotted-down-thoughts-and-images-we-left-there-stopped-through-a-shopping-center-then-headed-back-for-the-evening-we-spent-the-evening-going-through-the-mass-of-pictures-we-collected-over-the-last-five-days&#34;&gt;Following the museum we visited another garden, Covis Botanical, which is all volunteer run. This garden was very nice, especially to be completely run by volunteers. I sat for a while under a tree and jotted down thoughts and images. We left there, stopped through a shopping center, then headed back for the evening. We spent the evening going through the mass of pictures we collected over the last five days.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;a-lot-of-happy-pictures-of-happy-people-we-had-a-great-time-and-made-a-lot-of-good-memories-together-you-couldnt-have-asked-for-a-better-trip-with-friends-now-im-eager-to-visit-more-national-parks-weve-got-another-trip-planned-in-july-for-congerie-national-park-maybe-the-great-smokey-mountains-is-the-thing-to-start-planning&#34;&gt;A lot of happy pictures of happy people. We had a great time and made a lot of good memories together. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a better trip with friends. Now I&amp;rsquo;m eager to visit more National Parks, we&amp;rsquo;ve got another trip planned in July for Congerie National Park. Maybe the Great Smokey Mountains is the thing to start planning.&lt;/h6&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/the-national-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/the-national-parks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-national-parks&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;the national parks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;where-to-even-begin-the-last-few-days-have-been-so-packed-with-experiences-i-cant-keep-my-head-on-straight-i-reckon-ill-do-things-the-julie-andrews-way-and-start-from-the-very-beginning&#34;&gt;Where to even begin? The last few days have been so packed with experiences I can&amp;rsquo;t keep my head on straight. I reckon I&amp;rsquo;ll do things the Julie Andrews way and start from the very beginning.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;after-we-arrived-in-fresno-we-met-with-our-friends-and-got-our-car-for-dinner-we-had-in-n-out-which-for-most-of-us-was-our-first-time-the-way-they-chop-those-gigantic-potatoes-is-comical-and-hilarious-after-dinner-we-made-our-way-to-the-grocery-then-the-airbnb-and-crashed&#34;&gt;After we arrived in Fresno, we met with our friends and got our car. For dinner we had In-N-Out, which for most of us was our first time. The way they chop those gigantic potatoes is comical and hilarious. After dinner we made our way to the grocery then the AirBnb and crashed.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-next-morning-we-all-got-up-extra-early-for-our-long-drive-to-yosemite-national-park-we-got-to-see-most-of-the-big-hitters-el-capitan-the-half-dome-a-grove-of-giant-sequoias-meadows-and-waterfalls-we-got-so-wet-at-the-falls-everyone-was-grinning-like-a-dead-pig-and-had-the-giggles-at-the-yosemite-post-office-why-yes-there-is-a-post-office-in-the-park-i-got-my-notebook-stamped-with-the-special-note-they-have-for-mail-coming-out-of-the-park-the-drive-back-was-more-outrageous-than-the-drive-in-because-at-least-when-youre-driving-in-you-get-to-see-some-sights-at-night-its-pitch-black-in-them-hills&#34;&gt;The next morning we all got up extra early for our long drive to Yosemite National Park. We got to see most of the big hitters, El Capitan, the Half Dome, a grove of giant sequoias, meadows and waterfalls. We got so wet at the falls, everyone was grinning like a dead pig and had the giggles. At the Yosemite Post Office, why yes, there is a post office in the park, I got my notebook stamped with the special note they have for mail coming out of the park. The drive back was more outrageous than the drive in, because at least when you&amp;rsquo;re driving in, you get to see some sights. At night it&amp;rsquo;s pitch black in them hills.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;yesterday-we-made-our-way-to-sequoia-national-park-that-much-i-know-today-and-yesterday-are-kinda-running-together-for-me-because-were-getting-started-at-the-crack-of-dawn-and-crashing-at-11pm-we-went-through-the-foothills-of-the-park-and-saw-tunnel-rock-and-hospital-rock-then-made-our-way-up-to-higher-altitude-where-we-climbed-to-the-top-of-the-mountain-and-saw-some-really-neat-sequoias-we-hiked-back-down-so-we-could-then-visit-the-worlds-largest-tree-general-sherman-a-monument-to-say-the-least-however-we-were-all-quite-tired-at-that-point-and-had-some-more-places-in-mind-we-ended-the-day-by-watching-the-sunset-from-the-side-of-the-mountain-where-we-met-some-deer&#34;&gt;Yesterday we made our way to Sequoia National Park, that much I know. Today and yesterday are kinda running together for me because were getting started at the crack of dawn and crashing at 11PM. We went through the foothills of the park and saw Tunnel Rock and Hospital Rock then made our way up to higher altitude where we climbed to the top of the mountain and saw some really neat sequoias. We hiked back down so we could then visit the worlds largest tree, General Sherman. A monument to say the least, however we were all quite tired at that point and had some more places in mind. We ended the day by watching the sunset from the side of the mountain where we met some deer.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;today-we-fortunately-didnt-have-to-wait-on-a-road-closure-to-clear-up-for-us-to-get-into-the-main-area-of-sequoia-national-park-but-we-did-have-eminent-road-closures-due-to-a-winter-advisory-and-possible-snow-we-took-the-main-road-that-traverses-through-sequoia-and-into-formerly-known-as-grant-park-this-area-now-part-of-kings-canyon-has-another-one-of-the-largest-trees-in-the-world-the-second-to-be-more-specific-the-general-grant-tree-is-a-lot-more-impressive-in-my-opinion-than-the-sherman-tree-a-guide-explained-that-grant-grows-at-a-much-more-rapid-pace-than-sherman-so-if-all-goes-well-itll-be-the-largest-in-some-hundred-years-we-made-a-stop-on-the-way-out-of-kings-canyon-but-hustled-out-to-be-sure-the-road-didnt-close-on-us-lest-we-wanted-to-drive-out-around-our-elbow-to-get-to-our-ass-our-last-stop-was-tokopah-falls-the-hike-followed-marble-fork-of-kaweah-river-and-it-is-just-stunning-the-trail-is-likely-one-of-my-personal-favorites-as-we-approached-the-falls-it-slowly-began-to-snow-on-us-the-closer-we-got-the-more-it-snowed-we-made-it-right-up-to-a-great-view-of-the-falls-when-we-decided-to-turn-around-it-kept-snowing-it-kept-snowing-more-joshua-and-our-friends-were-getting-a-little-nervous-i-was-still-awestruck-beyond-worries-the-snow-was-beautiful-the-trees-were-beautiful-the-rapids-the-flurries-the-wet-soggy-soil-the-fog-the-clouds-the-wall-of-rock-scaling-your-whole-view-all-so-beautiful-we-made-it-back-safe-and-sound-no-tire-chains-needed-and-no-snow-on-the-roads&#34;&gt;Today we fortunately didn&amp;rsquo;t have to wait on a road closure to clear up for us to get into the main area of Sequoia National Park. But&amp;hellip; we did have eminent road closures due to a winter advisory and possible snow. We took the main road that traverses through Sequoia and into formerly known as Grant Park. This area, now part of Kings Canyon, has another one of the largest trees in the world, the second, to be more specific. The General Grant tree is a lot more impressive in my opinion than the Sherman tree. A guide explained that Grant grows at a much more rapid pace than Sherman, so if all goes well, it&amp;rsquo;ll be the largest in some hundred years. We made a stop on the way out of Kings Canyon, but hustled out to be sure the road didn&amp;rsquo;t close on us, lest we wanted to drive out around our elbow to get to our ass. Our last stop was Tokopah Falls. The hike followed Marble Fork of Kaweah River, and it is just stunning. The trail is likely one of my personal favorites. As we approached the falls, it slowly began to snow on us. The closer we got, the more it snowed. We made it right up to a great view of the falls, when we decided to turn around. It kept snowing. It kept snowing more. Joshua and our friends were getting a little nervous, I was still awestruck beyond worries. The snow was beautiful, the trees were beautiful, the rapids, the flurries, the wet soggy soil, the fog, the clouds, the wall of rock scaling your whole view. All so beautiful. We made it back safe and sound, no tire chains needed, and no snow on the roads.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;the-land-here-has-an-energy-that-is-hard-to-describe-with-words-its-serene-and-spiritual-monumental-and-cleansing-pure-and-sacred-theres-a-feeling-about-the-air-that-feels-like-a-spirit-of-some-kind-maybe-the-mountain-maybe-the-river-or-the-trees-its-hard-to-wrap-your-head-around-a-place-that-took-millions-of-years-to-develop-and-organisms-that-took-hundreds-or-even-thousands-of-years-to-grow-to-where-they-are-now-when-i-blink-i-see-flashes-of-the-seminal-landscape-that-we-were-so-fortunate-to-see-this-week-i-feel-overwhelmed-with-gratitude-in-this-moment-but-also-inspired-to-make-and-inspired-to-do-im-eager-to-see-what-come-of-this-experience&#34;&gt;The land here has an energy that is hard to describe with words. It&amp;rsquo;s serene and spiritual, monumental and cleansing, pure and sacred. There&amp;rsquo;s a feeling about the air that feels like a spirit of some kind, maybe the mountain, maybe the river, or the trees. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to wrap your head around a place that took millions of years to develop, and organisms that took hundreds, or even thousands of years to grow to where they are now. When I blink, I see flashes of the seminal landscape that we were so fortunate to see this week. I feel overwhelmed with gratitude in this moment but also inspired to make and inspired to do. I&amp;rsquo;m eager to see what come of this experience.&lt;/h6&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/california-girlie-pops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/california-girlie-pops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;california-girlie-pops&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;california girlie-pops&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;today-the-girlies-and-i-are-on-the-way-out-to-california-five-of-us-are-meeting-in-fresno-to-drive-out-to-an-accommodation-just-between-yosemite-kings-canyon-and-the-giant-sequoias-were-all-super-excited-to-experience-these-monuments-together-its-particularly-special-because-these-are-some-of-our-closest-friends-and-itll-be-one-of-the-last-big-things-we-get-to-do-together-while-we-all-live-in-georgia&#34;&gt;Today the girlies and I are on the way out to California. Five of us are meeting in Fresno to drive out to an accommodation just between Yosemite, Kings Canyon, and the Giant Sequoias. We&amp;rsquo;re all super excited to experience these monuments together. It&amp;rsquo;s particularly special because these are some of our closest friends, and it&amp;rsquo;ll be one of the last big things we get to do together while we all live in Georgia.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;joshua-planned-the-whole-thing-the-way-he-does-im-so-grateful-hes-headstrong-about-planning-because-i-am-not-i-want-it-all-to-just-happen-and-enjoy-the-ride-hes-so-excited-for-this-trip-hes-bought-binoculars-a-harness-a-new-flashlight-new-boots-jackets-the-whole-get-up-of-course-everything-that-can-be-is-in-the-color-green&#34;&gt;Joshua planned the whole thing, the way he does. I&amp;rsquo;m so grateful he&amp;rsquo;s headstrong about planning, because I am not. I want it all to just happen and enjoy the ride. He&amp;rsquo;s so excited for this trip; he&amp;rsquo;s bought binoculars, a harness, a new flashlight, new boots, jackets, the whole get-up. Of course, everything that can be is in the color green.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;ive-packed-a-notebook-i-made-especially-for-the-month-of-may-in-addition-to-my-regular-sketchbook-i-aim-to-take-both-out-to-the-parks-each-day-and-have-study-time-i-think-i-speak-for-most-of-us-when-i-say-we-need-time-to-sit-and-draw-and-write-a-professor-of-ours-always-says-writing-is-thinking-like-most-i-didnt-quite-get-the-advice-until-i-had-sat-with-it-and-experienced-it-for-myself-writing-is-thinking-but-drawing-is-too-as-visual-artists-we-all-need-the-time-to-sketch-ideas-jot-notes-and-study-the-world-by-translating-it-to-paper&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve packed a notebook I made especially for the month of May in addition to my regular sketchbook. I aim to take both out to the parks each day and have study time. I think I speak for most of us when I say we &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt; time to sit and draw and write. A professor of ours always says, &amp;ldquo;Writing is thinking.&amp;rdquo; Like most, I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get the advice until I had sat with it and experienced it for myself. Writing &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; thinking, but drawing is too. As visual artists, we all need the time to sketch ideas, jot notes, and study the world by translating it to paper.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;h6 id=&#34;ill-end-with-a-poem-i-wrote-for-someone-on-the-trip-their-birthday-was-yesterday&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll end with a poem I wrote for someone on the trip. Their birthday was yesterday.&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA;ardent instinct, namely sharp language, ensonorous yen.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;free as yon river, ever-nesting endeavors.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;so tend each edition, value eclipsed suns.&#xA;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/a-cool-late-summer-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/a-cool-late-summer-morning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cool late-summer morning, a sunday, and I&amp;rsquo;m sipping on my coffee that tastes like Columbus, Georgia. Having the windows open first thing in the morning is quite a treat, and I sadly anticipate the time of year this won&amp;rsquo;t be available.&#xA;Each morning I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to start the day off with mindfulness and body awareness. A breif meditation session followed by a radio taiso routine, sometimes I throw in some extra hamstring stretches at the end. This morning, I felt compelled to right for a bit before me and my new neighbor and friend, Annie, go for a run. It&amp;rsquo;s been nagging at be all year, this compulsion to right. The compulsion to read has be gnawing at my left ear just as much. Having treated myself to this new computer with this thocky keyboard, writing is just like eating a boston cream donut at the Brimfield Flea Market. That donut yesterday was something special. I&amp;rsquo;ve never in my life had a boston cream that rendered me speechless.&#xA;Joshua being in grad school means he&amp;rsquo;s got a lot to read, and one of those things is Bird by Bird by Anne Larmotte. She&amp;rsquo;s a writer, obviously, but also a writing coach. Bird by Bird is Lamotte&amp;rsquo;s advice column of a paperback on how to be a better, and more fulfilled writer. Her advice is exactly what my old mentor from undergrad preached, just make. Just make all the time. Make when you&amp;rsquo;re happy, make when you&amp;rsquo;re sad. Make the worst stuff you&amp;rsquo;ll ever make. Everything is a first draft, and no one has to see it. That&amp;rsquo;s why you make all the time, so you can take those first drafts and dress&amp;rsquo;em up a little as a second draft, then a third, then you got yourself a nice piece of writing. It&amp;rsquo;s good advice.&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I&amp;rsquo;ve been compelled to write so much lately. I feel my piney-south georgian accent screaming to be heard and paid some mind. The idiolect I had adopted in Columbus was good, it served it&amp;rsquo;s purpose, and I expanded my vocabulary there more than I imagined. But at the same time I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m forsaking my mama, my nana, and my grandma by givin&amp;rsquo; up words like &amp;lsquo;buggy&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;fixin&amp;rsquo;, and phrases I&amp;rsquo;ve already sent to this virtual peice of paper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/eleven-signatures-to-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/eleven-signatures-to-a-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;18-feb-2025&#34;&gt;18 FEB 2025&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;ll get to see him again. I asked if I could draw his body hair, something I was doing with mine in my studio. The body&amp;rsquo;s self adornments drawings are a reflection of intimacy. For myself, it marked some key moments where I began feeling confident in my skin and with the person I see in the mirror. The confidence stirred arousal, which in tern stirred more confidence. Intimacy with Will builds even more confidence. His verbal admirations make me grin and give warmth and content. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in learning about his body&amp;rsquo;s adornments and more about his person. Comfort, intimacy, contentment, solace, contact, satiety, climax, ease. The body displays these things with its hair, with its skin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/for-gena-to-play-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/for-gena-to-play-around/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;kudyfbweriufytwfuygeucfxherwuhfre;uohfweouightf ureghtaixcfuen;hjpaopimhjeruytgi7fgeiyu hfgjbvnfujdhbfsdxcjvbncxjkvb scjkxfdvbskjdv akj,sbcfvkasjdbjdvbuj      jknvgjdsvgujsbv  kljdbgvwsujdrbvuj    jdfvfjdvbdiusghwdefvuhb alsdknvcasdljvncsvkwsjdfrvn ksjdbvcsdbv sduyb ksjkdbncvnujdsabvcqwedca kjsxhcbvasxkihjucasecdvubgedaucvbgwiohgfwuierfhgwujhbskdjvbghsdifvuj2536486970 ehjdfbvhfdbvyhdbfshvbiksefrdhbjvgue3e76r4jsdhcvbsdjhcbvaaaavbchvdhvgbxcjahvbcdsajkihycgqevwacjkhasbcxjkm  asdjxcabahsbcjkhsgbcyhsgdcva ajhcvbasdjhgxcv sdyhgvc  ajshmcbvasjhc chsjvbcvhcdvchgvbasjbhn cjdjhvdjshvsadjcajsdyhcvgasjdhcbvjhvkjvbwdkvugb gdcfuadsiyg yuhgdcvius saidyucfgfwqediubcwqdjcjuhciwuecbecvdhgyfvcsdyvcsdjhvbdcsidyuyfiwsadhbcfsjdacduycgasdcidsakucvjashbdcvikd dcjhkdbcdjwhskbcb dvcijudkshb uyhdbgcvs hjjh hjdscbsdicyugc ujddxudgbbb vg bcnhcjoiasuhcdcubduhgfggbbubiubb ugbdwsudgwdjbnjasddojsabyudfghfgn nivhjhhfihf nnnvnvjhjfnvjkfhfoedjfdofuirnikrnfslsikvgnsgvfbnvdfbnjdfnbjkdnfkdjbdfgbvkdjbndfkjbn dfkjbndfkjbndkfjbnkdjfbn djkfhbvdfkjhbv fhkvbdkhjfbvhurv jfdvbn ujdfsvj vfsdjnbv vkdsfjbvfkhujbrfv dkjbvdfujvb&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/good-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/good-morning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I got to speak with my dear friend rfachael farren for the first time in a while. We spoke a while back on her birthday, but not for too long. Today it feels like old times where we would just sit on the phone with each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/passage-track-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/passage-track-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;16-feb-2025&#34;&gt;16 FEB 2025&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;over the last several months as i fall for will, i&amp;rsquo;ve started to solidify suspicions i had about myself. the capacity to be in love with someone is not limited to a singular person and a singular moment for me. i wrote not long after having a chat with joshua about this. he was encouraging and understanding. he seemed to be open to working through the idea of me holding romantic relationships external to ours.&#xA;the more my feelings grow for will, the more i worry about jealousy from joshua. he&amp;rsquo;s not a jealous person, i think it&amp;rsquo;s just my own fears that i have to let go. to hear him say fully that he&amp;rsquo;s fine with this would bring me so much peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/recency-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/recency-bias/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m being patient with myself as I work through the feelings I&amp;rsquo;m struggling with toward Joshua. He and I have been having a harder time lately, I think his stress is being directed at me. Recency bias attempts to cloud my judgement on the whole of the relationship, but I know he and I have something unlike most. We both understand on a deeper level that people have to learn how to love, even in a long-term relationship. We promised to be an enrichment to each other&amp;rsquo;s lives, and I feel we do that for each other. The recency bias just tries its darnedest to make me forget. I won&amp;rsquo;t let it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/salt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-salt-is-the-most-important-of-seasonings-it-makes-our-food-taste-like-anything-at-all-without-it-our-meals-boring-and-bland-it-enriches-all-it-touches-giving-a-dish-life-when-it-rains-it-pours-a-pinch-here-a-teaspoon-there-ive-no-measurable-amount-of-gratitude-for-the-salt-youve-enriched-my-life-with&#34;&gt;for salt is the most important of seasonings. it makes our food taste like anything at all. without it, our meals boring and bland. it enriches all it touches, giving a dish life. when it rains, it pours. a pinch here, a teaspoon there. i&amp;rsquo;ve no measurable amount of gratitude for the salt you&amp;rsquo;ve enriched my life with.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I began working on this print for the faculty who I feel made an impact on my life as a student and as it carried over into the full time job at CSU. Without their support, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where I am now with Kate. I&amp;rsquo;ve got fourteen of the &lt;em&gt;plain&lt;/em&gt; ones, two on a tan paper, and a few more on the way on a different tan paper. I remade one specifically for my Mama, because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite the right ratio for the frame I put together for her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/01/the-chattahoochee-valley-beats-like-a-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/01/the-chattahoochee-valley-beats-like-a-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-chattahoochee-valley-beats-like-a-heart&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;the chattahoochee valley beats like a heart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As many are aware at this point, Joshua and I have made the decision to move to Connecticut. He&amp;rsquo;s enrolling in an MFA program at UCONN this fall. I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited for him, but also for myself. He&amp;rsquo;s needed space and time to make more now than ever. His feet are off the ground with interesting ideas and he seriously needs the facility and time to explore these ideas further. I&amp;rsquo;m quite proud of him, he is becoming more of himself, and it makes me love him more and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
