<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>journal on the papers</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in journal on the papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>salt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/salt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;for salt is the most important of seasonings. it makes our food taste like anything at all. without it, our meals boring and bland. it enriches all it touches, giving a dish life. when it rains, it pours. a pinch here, a teaspoon there. i&amp;rsquo;ve no measurable amount of gratitude for the salt you&amp;rsquo;ve enriched my life with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>birds on the roof</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/birds-on-the-roof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/birds-on-the-roof/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The little house sparrows keep oscillating from the bush out front to the ledge of the roof. Occasionally their wings all flutter at the same moment resulting in a sound that almost resembles sudden rainfall.&#xA;The coffee was pretty good this morning, I quite like the one I got from the local co-op.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a cool late-summer morning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/a-cool-late--summer-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/a-cool-late--summer-morning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cool late-summer morning, a sunday, and I&amp;rsquo;m sipping on my coffee that tastes like Columbus, Georgia. Having the windows open first thing in the morning is quite a treat, and I sadly anticipate the time of year this won&amp;rsquo;t be available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>northeast corridor life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/northeast-corridor-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/northeast-corridor-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been in Connecticut for just over a week now. Settling in has definitely had its stressful moments, but  overall the move has been smooth. Our friends Ainsley and Gena arrived last Saturday to help us get the bulk of unpacking done. All four of us have moved within the last three months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>things of sequoia trails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/think-about-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 19:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/think-about-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h6 id=&#34;yall-said-it&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;y&amp;rsquo;all said it!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h6&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;THERE ARE ORANGE TREES EVERYWHERE IN THE SAN JUAQUIN VALLEY&#xA;&#39;EVERYBODY THERE IS SO NICE&#39;&#xA;&#39;I REALLY ADMIRE THAT YOU LIKE PHYSICS&#39;&#xA;&#39;WE HAVE STICK AT HOME!&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>heading home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/heading-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/heading-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sitting at the airport right now waiting for our first of two flights to get home. Yesterday we had a pretty easy day. With the winter advisory stil in effect for most of the parks, we didn&amp;rsquo;t feels safe going back for the last day. You could see the storms in the mountains from our accomodation. That morning, we made a big breakfast to try and use up as many groceries as we could.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the national parks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/the-national-parks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/the-national-parks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-national-parks&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;the national parks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Where to even begin? The last few days have been so packed with experiences I can&amp;rsquo;t keep my head on straight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>california girlie-pops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/california-girlie--pops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/california-girlie--pops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the girlies and I are on the way out to California. Five of us are meeting in Fresno to drive out to an accommodation just between Yosemite, Kings Canyon, and the Giant Sequoias. We&amp;rsquo;re all super excited to experience these monuments together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the chattahoochee valley beats like a heart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/the-chattahoochee-valley-beats-like-a-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 10:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/journal/the-chattahoochee-valley-beats-like-a-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many are aware at this point, Joshua and I have made the decision to move to Connecticut. He&amp;rsquo;s enrolling in an MFA program at UCONN this fall. I&amp;rsquo;m quite excited for him, but also for myself. He&amp;rsquo;s needed space and time to make more now than ever. His feet are off the ground with interesting ideas and he seriously needs the facility and time to explore these ideas further. I&amp;rsquo;m quite proud of him, he is becoming more of himself, and it makes me love him more and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
